# SHUBH AGGARWAL

**J** 8800720847

■ agarwalshubhofficial@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/shubhaggarwal

#### About Me

Dedicated and industrious, bringing over a year of invaluable experience in the dynamic realm of software engineering. Proficient across an array of programming languages including C, C++, C#, Python, and Java, possessing a skill set primed for tackling diverse challenges. Committed to continuous growth, embracing each day as an opportunity to expand my expertise and stay abreast of emerging technologies.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Moody's Analytics Gurgaon, India Jul 2023 - Present Software Engineer

- Enhanced and maintained a critical software product used by many big banks, leading to a 35% increase in user satisfaction and reducing system downtime by 20% within eight months.
- Architected scalable server-side solutions with C# reformed UI/UX with Angular, and maintained integrity of extensive datasets in PostgreSQL, resulting in an increase in application efficiency and user satisfaction.
- Drive product development initiatives, addressing defects and aligning solutions with client feedback and requirements.
- Established extensive unit testing procedures after feature development, guaranteeing superior performance and reliability, decreased post-launch issues by 55% and increased client satisfaction score.
- Identified and addressed client needs by working closely with product owners, provided accurate estimations that led to timely project completion and a 30% increase in project delivery efficiency.
- Cultivated a strong team by implementing structured communicating protocol, resolved 95% of project challenges collaboratively and boosting team efficiency and project completion rate by 60%.

**HighRadius** Remote, India Jan 2022 – Apr 2022 Internship

- Designed and implemented a full-stack web based product for SaaS environment during an internship at High Radius Corporation, resulting in a reduction in project development time and boosted user engagement by 50% through improved
- Spearheaded a comprehensive analysis of the product development lifecycle, identifying critical user requirements that informed the design process, resulting in massive increase in user satisfaction scores post-launch.

### **Technical Skills**

**Programming Languages:** C, C++, C#, Python, Java

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL

Version Control: Git, GitHub, GitHub Copilot Developer Tools: VS Code, Visual Studio, Dbeaver

Miscellaneous: Jenkins, Angular, Debugging, Data Analytics, Product Development, Unit Testing and Presentation Skills

### **Projects**

# A Travelling Website

Designed and developed a fully responsive travel website using HTML and CSS.

### **Big Mart Sales Prediction**

- Developed a robust machine learning algorithm to analyze sales trends across diverse cities, processing 10,000 data points to identify key purchasing items, directly optimizing promotional strategies for increase customer engagement.
- Interpreted datasets to generate actionable sights, leading to strategic recommendations that enhanced decision making processes and hence impacting overall efficiency across departments.

# **Credit Card Fraud Detection**

- Conducted a comprehensive analysis on a credit card transaction dataset, encompassing diverse transactions by numerous customers.
- This undertaking underscored my proficiency in leveraging advanced analytical techniques to ensure the security and integrity of financial transactions.

### Education

## SRM Institute of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

Jul 2019 – May 2023 CGPA: 9.57

## CH. Chhabil Dass Public School

Higher Secondary Education in PCM

Apr 2018 - May 2019 Percentage: 86.8

# Awards and Recognition

Top Graduate Performer – Recognized as one of the top performers among new graduates, for exceptional contribution to product development using server-side technologies. Played a key role in enhancing team productivity and driving the success of critical projects.

### Certificates

- Programming with C++
- Google Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- IBM Introduction to Data Analytics